what's going on ladies and gentlemen
welcome back to another one and in this
video we're doing a little bit of a
product review we're going to jump right
into it today we're reviewing one of my
favorite reels out there it's actually
the fluger president and now these
things are awesome okay at a very
affordable reel you can do some damage
with these things okay the uh newest
model that they came out with looks a
little bit different than the old one
but they seem to be awesome it comes
with an all graphite body and there's
not a bit of plastic on this thing they
are absolutely awesome this reel is
extremely lightweight this is the 25
series so it's actually a 10 ball
stainless steel ball bearing system
which for this size reel is really
really good okay now if you do size down
if you go to a 20 sized reel or
something smaller I believe there's only
seven bearings which isn't really the
end of the world but all in all it seems
to be pretty good so we're going to jump
into things we're going to talk about
what we think of it hopefully we can
catch some fish today too We're Just
Fishing Off the dock throwing a little
weightless Seno so we'll see where we're
at it's raining a little bit I'm hoping
rain holds off so that we can catch some
fish and talk about this thing so let's
jump into it one thing that's super nice
about this reel is it's got an aluminum
handle and the uh reel on it is super
smooth you don't have to worry about
slipping your hand off of it it's very
soft touch and it's all aluminum there's
not a bit of plastic on this thing and
it just seems to be a really high
quality reel the uh spool is all carbon
and you don't have to worry about your
braid slipping out it it comes braid
ready there's there's rubber stops
inside of the spool so you don't have to
tie a mono backer floral backer or
anything like that it's just ready to go
and this thing casts far I have like a
10 lb fluorocarbon on here and I can
Chuck this thing way out there right I
mean that's a pretty darn good size cast
for such a light lure I mean not bad at
all it reels incredibly smoothly and the
design of it super slick I love the gold
on the handle and the black and blue and
silver just makes looks super sharp I
did queue it up with my Abu Garcia
Vengeance a 7t medium action Rod if you
guys want to check that out I'll link it
above because I did do a product review
on that as well and I think it makes a
very good combo I would entertain
putting some braid on this reel I think
I might switch to braid I do kind of
like fishing braided line a little bit
more than fluro but um all in all it
seems okay I don't actually even have
enough fluro Carbon on this spool but
it's getting the job done for today but
super nice stopping power there when you
reel it that doesn't push back on you or
anything like that there is actually
something that they call line control on
this reel it's supposed to eliminate
line twist I haven't used it enough to
actually see for sure if the line does
twist or not um but one thing that's
super cool about this reel it's the
newer design for the fluger president
they did have an older design and
honestly that seemed fine too some of
the major differences I know that they
had a foam grip on the fluger presidence
before and this one's rubber which is
kind of nice it feels feels like it's
going to hold up a lot better over time
and your you know the handle on your
reel isn't going to fall off or
something other than that I don't see a
whole lot of differences other than the
color and that kind of thing um I think
the bearings are the same too so they
kind of just changed the design of it um
which is nice you to know that it's
still the same quality reel um they do
come at a they did seem to raise the
price a little bit just kind of like
everything else you can pick these reels
up for $69.95 I believe um at your local
Outfitter or whatever you can probably
buy the older style reel still for like
50 bucks something like that which is a
heck of a deal because they're really
really nice reels and I do think that
this new one does seem to be pretty
topnotch the drag system on it seems to
be super smooth I can tighten her way
down and you got plenty of drag on there
to reel in anything big so no issues
with that I don't have really any
complaints with it I think it's going to
be a real that I'm going to keep in my
Arsenal for a long time I don't quite
know if it's going to fall into the
budget reel category just because it is
like 60 or 70 bucks um unless you get it
on sale it is a little higher priced so
I don't think it's going to fall under
that budget category so we're still kind
of on the hunt for the best budget reel
we can find but I do like this reel and
I think I'm going to use it for a long
long time the accuracy with it seems to
be pretty spot-on and all in all I just
like it I like the look of it I like the
feel of it the grip is nice you can hold
on to it really really good and it
doesn't feel like it's going to fall
apart on you or anything like that which
is very positive the aluminum spool
seems super nice it seems to hold the
line really really well it doesn't seem
like it's going to break apart or
anything like that and with the slow
oscillation that you do get from this
reel it operates very nicely and I
believe that the gear ratio is a 521 on
this guy which is kind of to be expected
um especially for a 10 bearing system it
definitely seems to meet the
expectations of what I was thinking when
I was going to buy this re I uh I would
definitely put this into the category as
like a higher end better option for you
know if you're looking for a good
quality reel I think this is definitely
it they're super clean super nice I
really don't have anything bad to say
about it the only thing that it doesn't
have is the switch to toggle to go to um
Go reverse with your line you can't run
the handle back and forth which I've
been noticing a lot of the new reels
nowadays are getting away from that um
I'm sure there's a reason behind it I
mean I never really used it anyway so
that's probably why they're getting rid
of it I guess the one thing that I did
notice about this reel which I thought
was kind of odd I mean maybe it's just
me maybe I'm just looking at it wrong
but I feel like for a 25 series reel I
do feel like it's a little small I know
I have some other like 2500 or 25 series
reels and they just seem a little bit
bigger so I don't know if fluger
downsizes on their reels for some reason
but it seems like you could pretty
easily go up to a 30 size reel if you're
doing like Bass or something like that I
mean with that said I mean it's going to
do all that you need it to but it just
seems kind of odd that it's not bigger I
don't know maybe it's just me but it I
mean what do you guys think does it look
a little does it look a little small I
think it maybe does I don't know but all
in all I love this thing and if you guys
are looking for a highquality reel I
would definitely look at this fluger
President I will link it below in the
description if you guys want to check it
out um seems to be a very good Contender
of quality reels um and coming in at 70
it's really all not that badly priced
for the quality that you're getting into
this reel there's no plastic components
it's all carbon it's all graphite
aluminum it really just seems to be
pretty solid all in all though guys if
you guys are looking for a very
affordable high quality fishing reel I
would definitely I would definitely
check out the fluger president these
things seem pretty awesome and honestly
for $69.95 you kind of can't beat it uh
spinning reels can get really expensive
you know especially if you're looking at
you know other brands and that kind of
stuff but fluger has a pretty great name
for themselves and I would not be afraid
to check out the fluger president I'll
link it down below I hope you guys
enjoyed the video and if you did make
sure you smash that subscribe button and
like the video and we'll see you guys in
the next one peace